RAÚL ELIZALDE BRETON

Data Engineer / Web Developer

(+521) 33 1320 2091 raul.elizalde.breton@gmail.com

https://github.com/raulbreton

in/raul-elizalde-breton-2172081a 6

Technical skills

IBM Data Stage

Google Cloud Platform

ETL

Python Data Analysis

Python Web Development

Python Object Oriented

Programming

HTML/CSS

SQL

Linux

Git / Github

Languages

English

TOEIC "International Proficiency" Certificate (920/990 pts.)

French

B1 DELF

About myself

I'm a technology enthusiast with over two years of experience in software development and data analysis who believes in working ethics and being a good co-worker. I take pride in my ability to deliver high-quality software solutions and have productive communication during the development process with my co-workers.

Job Experience

IBM / Jr. Data Engineer

JULY 2022 - AUGUST 2023; GUADALAJARA, JALISCO

I successfully contributed to IBM's Financial Department Data Warehouse, conducting detailed analyses using DB2 Big SQL Queries. With my expertise and in collaboration with the team, data jobs were executed, edited, and created efficiently, facilitating the prompt delivery of visualizations upon request.

University of Guadalajara / Full Stack Web Developer

JANUARY 2023 - SEPTEMBER 2023; GUADALAJARA, JALISCO

Selected to develop a website within the Research Coordination of the university to streamline its processes, aiming to facilitate documents requested by graduate students and alumni. Employed tools included Google Cloud Platform, Django, HTML with Bootstrap support, and PostgreSQL. Led requirement gathering directly with the department head, creating a Software Engineering and utilizing the Scrum methodology for project development management.

Education / Academic Background

Universidad de Guadalajara / Software Engineering

JANUARY 2019 - JULY 2023; GUADALAJARA, JALISCO

Actively engaged in algorithm clubs and seminars to enhance algorithm efficiency and participated in internal club contests to test my programming knowledge. Through active involvement and mentorship from a professor who recognized my abilities, I secured my initial position at IBM. Subsequently, through a university-led initiative, I was chosen to develop applications for the University's Research Coordination. This experience allowed me to showcase my leadership skills as I managed the project from requirement gathering to product delivery.